

JOHAN JACOBS Graphic Designer

Date of birth: February 3, 1976
Location: Bloemfontein,
Free State

Phone: +27 71 675 5341 E-mail: jjacobs064@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://johanj76.github.io/mobirise/index.html

At least 16 years experience in graphic designing and 2 years experience in newspaper print production process. I am a talented, ambitious and hardworking individual, with versatile skills and have experience working as part of a team and individually. Furthermore, I am able to handle multiple tasks on a daily basis and use a creative approach to problem solving. Other key strengths are that I am always energetic and eager to learn new skills. Strong attention to detail and ability to work effectively under pressure and meet tight deadlines.

Deliver all projects in a timely fashion. I am always on time for organised events, work-related or otherwise. Always highly enthused about my work and tasks ahead and understand the importance of being interactive and enjoy communicating with others for the benefit of the company and clients. I work with the team to provide imaginative solutions for customers. Co-workers rely on me to be on time. Even though I take my work seriously, I do have a good sense of humor. I have confidence in others and approach new challenges with an open mind.

RÉSUMÉ

EMPLOYMENT

Paarlcoldset / Novus Holdings - Bloemfontein CTP Operator 1/4/2016 - 31/4/2018

- Managing the digital workflow processes of material received from clients.
- Communicating and interacting with clients and other relevant production personnel in the organization.
- Ensuring quality standards are adhered to. Troubleshooting and fault finding.
- Ensure record keeping and weekly stock taking is done according to expected standards.
- Keeping abreast of new innovations and technological developments and improvements in the pre-press domain.
- Carrying out routine maintenance procedures on all CTP equipment.
- Ensure that quality plates are produced on time in full to the Press Department.
- Quality Control Champion going through newspapers the press printed on quality, defects and record info in MIS. Complete day-2-day record on quality are kept and send to managers.

Volksblad / Media24 - Bloemfontein

Graphic Designer / Team Leader

1/2/2000 - 31/3/2016

- Design day-to-day adverts for clients advertising within the Volksblad group.
- Design promotional work for Volksblad group posters, logo's, banners, business cards, digital adverts, etc.
- Managing digital material received from clients.
- Retouching and deep etching of photos for editorial- and DTP-department.
- Co-ordinating workflow from ADS to desired departments in Pre-Press.
- Ensuring quality standards are kept in DTP department.
- Monitoring newspapers to ensure they meet their deadlines for print and sending final pages to CTP department for printing.
- Troubleshooting and fault finding if a query comes through.
- Team leader for Pre-Press managing all departments in DTP.
- Communicating and interacting with relevant production personnel and managers within the organization.

ARTISTIC SKILLS



PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Photoshop

80%

Corel Draw

80%

Indesign

50%

Illustrator

40%

Microsoft Office

60%

Dreamweaver

40%

40% After Effects

Adobe Muse

Adobe Lightroom

40%

HTML 30% CSS

40%

EMPLOYMENT

🧕 Foto & Video House - Bloemfontein

Part Time Graphic Designer

31/1/1999 - 1/12/1999

Designed logo's, DVD covers and promotional work.

Coffee Photography **■** Music RC Cars Movies

HOBBIES

EDUCATION

Central University of Technology - FS

National Diploma in Graphic Design

Louis Botha Technical High School - FS

Metric / Senior Certificate



ACHIEVEMENTS

Volksblad / Media24 - Bloemfontein

2015 - 15 Years Service Certificate

2015 - Promoted to Team Leader for Pre-Press Department

2015 - Graphic Designer of the Year Award

2010 - 10 Years Service Certificate

2010 - Graphic Designer of the Year Award

2004 - Promoted to Head Designer

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Afrikaans

English

000

REVERENCES

Volksblad / Media24 - Bloemfontein

Jeannine van Zyl - Bloemfontein Manager 051 404 7855

jvanzyl2@Volksblad.com

Lawrence Mokoena - Human Resources 051 404 7917

Lawrence.Mokoena@volksblad.com

Coleen Cilliers - Bethlehem Manager 058 303 5411

coleen@volksblad.com

Ludwig Esau - DTP Team Leader Volksblad 081 430 7950

lesau@Volksblad.com

Paarlcoldset

Mossie Mostert - General Manager 051 411 6861

Mossie.Mostert@paarlcoldset.co.za

Ndate Magwaza - Print Manager 051 411 6861

Ndate.Magwaza@paarlcoldset.co.za

Frikkie van der Walt - CTP Foreman 051 411 6865

frikkie.vanderwalt@paarlcoldset.co.za



JOHAN JACOBS

Graphic Designer

Date of birth: February 3, 1976 Location: Bloemfontein, Free State

Phone: +27 71 675 5341 E-mail: jjacobs064@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://johanj76.github.io/mobirise/index.html

At least 16 years experience in graphic designing and 2 years experience in newspaper print production process. I am a talented, ambitious and hardworking individual, with versatile skills and have experience working as part of a team and individually. Furthermore, I am able to handle multiple tasks on a daily basis and use a creative approach to problem solving. Other key strengths are that I am always energetic and eager to learn new skills. Strong attention to detail and ability to work effectively under pressure and meet tight deadlines.

Deliver all projects in a timely fashion. I am always on time for organised events, work-related or otherwise. Always highly enthused about my work and tasks ahead and understand the importance of being interactive and enjoy communicating with others for the benefit of the company and clients. I work with the team to provide imaginative solutions for customers. Co-workers rely on me to be on time. Even though I take my work seriously, I do have a good sense of humor. I have confidence in others and approach new challenges with an open mind.

RÉSUMÉ

✓ EMPLOYMENT

Paarlcoldset / Novus Holdings - Bloemfontein CTP Operator 1/4/2016 - 31/4/2018

- Managing the digital workflow processes of material received from clients.
- Communicating and interacting with clients and other relevant production personnel in the organization.
- · Ensuring quality standards are adhered to. Troubleshooting and fault finding.
- Ensure record keeping and weekly stock taking is done according to expected standards
- Keeping abreast of new innovations and technological developments and improvements in the pre-press domain.
- · Carrying out routine maintenance procedures on all CTP equipment.
- Ensure that quality plates are produced on time in full to the Press Department.
- Quality Control Champion going through newspapers the press printed on quality, defects and record info in MIS. Complete day-2-day record on quality are kept and send to managers.

Volksblad / Media24 - Bloemfontein Graphic Designer / Team Leader 1/2/2000 - 31/3/2016

- · Design day-to-day adverts for clients advertising within the Volksblad group.
- Design promotional work for Volksblad group posters, logo's, banners, business cards, digital adverts, etc.
- · Managing digital material received from clients.
- Retouching and deep etching of photos for editorial- and DTP-department.
- · Co-ordinating workflow from ADS to desired departments in Pre-Press.
- Ensuring quality standards are kept in DTP department.
- Monitoring newspapers to ensure they meet their deadlines for print and sending final pages to CTP department for printing.
- Troubleshooting and fault finding if a query comes through.
- Team leader for Pre-Press managing all departments in DTP.
- Communicating and interacting with relevant production personnel and managers within the organization.

ARTISTIC SKILLS Advertising >>>> **Branding** > > > >> Colour Theory **Editorial Design** Illustration >>> Infographics >>>> Logo Design >>>> **Typography** PROGRAMMING SKILLS **Photoshop Corel Draw** Indesign Illustrator **Microsoft Office** Dreamweaver 40% **After Effects Adobe Muse** 40% **Adobe Lightroom** HTML

EMPLOYMENT

- Foto & Video House Bloemfontein **Part Time Graphic Designer** 31/1/1999 - 1/12/1999
- Designed logo's, DVD covers and promotional work.

HOBBIES

- Coffee Photography Music
- **RC Cars** Movies

EDUCATION

- Central University of Technology FS National Diploma in Graphic Design
- **Louis Botha Technical High School FS** Metric / Senior Certificate

ACHIEVEMENTS

Volksblad / Media24 - Bloemfontein

2015 - 15 Years Service Certificate

2015 - Promoted to Team Leader for Pre-Press Department

2015 - Graphic Designer of the Year Award

2010 - 10 Years Service Certificate

2010 - Graphic Designer of the Year Award

2004 - Promoted to Head Designer

REVERENCES

Volksblad / Media24 - Bloemfontein Jeannine van Zyl - Bloemfontein Manager 051 404 7855 jvanzyl2@Volksblad.com

Lawrence Mokoena - Human Resources 051 404 7917

Lawrence.Mokoena@volksblad.com

Coleen Cilliers - Bethlehem Manager 058 303 5411

coleen@volksblad.com

Ludwig Esau - DTP Team Leader Volksblad 081 430 7950

lesau@Volksblad.com

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Afrikaans English

Paarlcoldset

Mossie Mostert - General Manager 051 411 6861

Mossie.Mostert@paarlcoldset.co.za

Ndate Magwaza - Print Manager 051 411 6861

Ndate.Magwaza@paarlcoldset.co.za

Frikkie van der Walt - CTP Foreman 051 411 6865

frikkie.vanderwalt@paarlcoldset.co.za